Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn.
我是Kathryn。
And Marco, I can tell you right now, I'm already hungry just thinking about our lesson today.
Marco，我现在就可以告诉你，光是想到今天的课程，我就已经饿了。
That's right.
没错。
Today we have another food lesson.
今天我们还有一节关于食物的课程。
Our world cuisine lesson for today is all about Mexican food.
今天的世界美食课程全部是关于墨西哥菜的。
Okay.
好的。
Mexican food comes from the country Mexico, but also parts of the United States like Texas
墨西哥菜来自墨西哥这个国家，但美国的一些地方，比如德克萨斯州，
have something called Tex-Mex.
也有一种叫“Tex-Mex”的菜系。
So you're going to hear a lot about these kinds of foods there.
所以你会听到很多关于这些食物的内容。
Let's check out today's dialogue.
我们来看看今天的对话。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
Welcome to Pistolero Restaurant.
欢迎来到Pistolero餐厅。
May I take your order?
请问可以点餐了吗？
Yes, I would like the chicken cheese enchiladas with a side of guacamole.
是的，我想要鸡肉奶酪卷饼，配上一份鳄梨酱。
Sorry sir, but we ran out of chicken.
抱歉，先生，我们的鸡肉卖完了。
May I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese quesadillas?
我可以推荐我们的美味牛肉卷饼或奶酪馅饼吗？
Both include a side of guacamole and jalapenos.
两者都配有鳄梨酱和墨西哥辣椒。
Sure, I'll have the burrito.
好的，我要牛肉卷饼。
Do you have nachos?
你们有玉米片吗？
Of course, sir.
当然有，先生。
Our nachos come with melted cheese and chili.
我们的玉米片配有融化的奶酪和辣椒。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Would you like anything to drink?
您想喝点什么吗？
Sure, I'll have a Corona.
好的，我要一瓶科罗娜啤酒。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of great dishes from Mexico.
所以有很多来自墨西哥的美味菜肴。
Let's take a closer look at some of those on Language Takeaway.
让我们在“语言小贴士”环节中仔细看看其中的一些。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So first up, Marco, we have the word enchilada.
首先，Marco，我们有“enchilada”这个词。
That's right.
没错。
We have some chicken cheese enchiladas.
我们有一些鸡肉奶酪卷饼。
So this dish has chicken and cheese, but an enchilada, what is that?
所以这道菜有鸡肉和奶酪，但“enchilada”到底是什么？
Okay, so it's basically a wrap that is covered in cheese, right?
好的，它基本上是一种裹着奶酪的卷饼，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So it has a base of a flour tortilla.
所以它的基底是面粉玉米饼。
So a tortilla is like a wrap, as you said.
所以玉米饼就像你说的，是一种卷饼。
Let's consider it as flat bread.
我们可以把它看作是一种扁平面包。
Very thin.
非常薄。
And it rolls up and it's covered with cheese and inside it has chicken.
然后它卷起来，上面覆盖着奶酪，里面包着鸡肉。
Very, very good.
非常非常好吃。
That's right.
没错。
So this is the beginning, you're going to hear me say the American pronunciation, enchilada,
所以一开始，你会听到我用美式发音说“enchilada”，
and you're going to hear Marco say a more appropriate.
而你会听到Marco用更地道的发音。
A little bit with a more Hispanic accent to it.
带一点西班牙语口音。
That's right.
没错。
So the second one we've got is guacamole.
第二个词是“guacamole”。
Guacamole.
鳄梨酱。
That's right.
没错。
We say guacamole and this is from the avocado fruit.
我们说“guacamole”，它来自鳄梨这种水果。
That's right.
没错。
Avocados are green fruits.
鳄梨是绿色的水果。
They have a skin.
它们有皮。
So you take the skin off and you usually mix guacamole with other ingredients.
所以你把皮去掉，通常会把鳄梨酱和其他配料混合在一起。
Right.
对。
A little bit of lemon, onion, tomato.
加一点柠檬、洋葱、番茄。
Maybe a little spice.
可能再加一点香料。
Really good stuff.
真的很好吃。
So yeah, it comes from that fruit that you said and it's kind of like a paste, right?
所以是的，它来自你说的那种水果，而且有点像糊状，对吧？
Yeah, it's something that we often use as a dip.
是的，我们经常用它作为蘸酱。
So I can dip my potato chips or my tortilla chips in it or I can use it as a sauce.
所以我可以蘸薯片或玉米片吃，或者也可以当酱料用。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And our next and probably one of the most popular dishes in the Mexican cuisine world
下一个，可能是墨西哥美食界最受欢迎的菜肴之一，
is a beef burrito.
就是牛肉卷饼。
Burrito.
卷饼。
So a burrito is another kind of wrap.
所以卷饼是另一种卷饼。
We have a tortilla like you said earlier and inside there are many different things.
我们有一个像你之前说的玉米饼，里面有很多不同的东西。
So usually some rice and some beans and some meat, maybe beef or chicken.
所以通常有一些米饭、豆子和肉，可能是牛肉或鸡肉。
That's right.
没错。
So consider it kind of like a sandwich more or less.
所以可以把它大致看作是一种三明治。
But in a blanket instead of in bread.
但用的是面饼而不是面包。
Exactly.
正是。
In a blanket.
用面饼。
And then also we have cheese quesadillas.
然后我们还有奶酪馅饼。
Now also these are made from the same blanket of tortilla.
这些也是用同样的面饼做的。
That's right.
没错。
So this thin tortilla, this flour tortilla is put on top and on bottom and inside you
所以这种薄薄的玉米饼，这种面粉玉米饼，上下各放一层，里面放上
have some cheese, some melted cheese or other times you can have cheese and chicken.
来点奶酪，一些融化的奶酪，或者有时候你也可以加奶酪和鸡肉。
And usually you find it's a circle but it's cut into four pieces.
通常你会发现它是一个圆形，但被切成四块。
So it looks like pieces of a pie.
所以看起来像馅饼的块。
That's right.
没错。
And what you do is you heat it up in a pan so the cheese inside melts and it's very,
你要做的是在平底锅里加热，这样里面的奶酪就会融化，而且非常，
very delicious.
非常美味。
It is.
是的。
And sometimes you have this with a side of jalapeno.
有时候你会配上一些墨西哥辣椒。
Okay.
好的。
This is some type of vegetable I would guess.
我猜这是一种蔬菜。
It's a pepper.
它是一种辣椒。
Right.
对。
So this is a very, very spicy pepper that people often use to make things taste hot.
这是一种非常非常辣的辣椒，人们经常用它来让食物变辣。
That's right.
没错。
So you can see them.
所以你可以看到它们。
They're usually green and they're very, very spicy.
它们通常是绿色的，而且非常非常辣。
So if you bite into one, it'll burn your mouth.
所以如果你咬一口，它会辣得你嘴巴发烫。
It will.
是的。
And sometimes people like to put these on our next dish.
有时候人们喜欢把这些放在我们的下一道菜上。
What's the next dish, Marco?
下一道菜是什么，Marco？
We have some nachos.
我们有玉米片。
Okay.
好的。
This is a classic Tex-Mex dish like I was saying.
就像我说的，这是一道经典的德州墨西哥菜。
So a lot of Americans love to eat this.
所以很多美国人都喜欢吃这个。
And nachos are basically a plate of tortilla chips with what on top?
玉米片基本上是一盘玉米片，上面有什么？
Usually it has melted cheese and maybe some chili like we see in the dialogue.
通常上面有融化的奶酪，也许还有一些辣椒，就像我们在对话中看到的那样。
So it will kind of just consider a plate full of these chips.
所以它基本上就是满满一盘这样的薯片。
They look like potato chips, but they're made out of flour.
它们看起来像薯片，但它们是面粉做的。
And on top a lot of cheese and maybe some meat or some chili on top.
上面有很多奶酪，也许还有一些肉或辣椒。
And Americans also like to put sour cream on top.
美国人也喜欢在上面加酸奶油。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
Sour cream is very popular on this dish.
酸奶油在这道菜上很受欢迎。
So a lot of dishes, these are probably the most popular ones that you can find at most
所以很多菜，这些可能是你在大多数
Mexican restaurants and also in Tex-Mex style cuisine.
墨西哥餐厅以及德州墨西哥风味菜系中最常见的。
So why don't we take another look at everything and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
那我们再回顾一下所有内容，稍后回来进行流利度训练。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
Welcome to Pistolero Restaurant.
欢迎来到Pistolero餐厅。
May I take your order?
我可以为您点餐吗？
Yes, I would like the chicken cheese enchiladas with a side of guacamole.
是的，我想要鸡肉奶酪玉米卷饼，配上一份鳄梨酱。
Sorry, sir, but we ran out of chicken.
抱歉，先生，我们的鸡肉卖完了。
May I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese quesadillas?
我可以推荐我们美味的牛肉卷饼或奶酪玉米饼吗？
Both include a side of guacamole and jalapenos.
两者都配有一份鳄梨酱和墨西哥辣椒。
Sure, I'll have the burrito.
好的，我要卷饼。
Do you have nachos?
你们有玉米片吗？
Of course, sir.
当然有，先生。
Our nachos come with melted cheese and chili.
我们的玉米片配有融化的奶酪和辣椒。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Would you like anything to drink?
您想喝点什么吗？
Sure, I'll have a Corona.
好的，我要一杯科罗娜啤酒。
All right, so Marco, today we have only three things to talk about in Fluency Builder.
好的，Marco，今天我们在流利度训练中只有三件事要讨论。
The first one is something that the waiter said to the customer.
第一件是服务员对顾客说的一句话。
It was to run out of.
是“用完了”。
That's right.
没错。
He wanted some chicken cheese enchiladas, but unfortunately they ran out of chicken.
他想要一些鸡肉奶酪玉米卷饼，但不幸的是他们的鸡肉卖完了。
So the phrasal verb here is to run out of.
所以这里的短语动词是“用完了”。
That's right, and we heard the past tense.
没错，我们听到的是过去式。
So unfortunately, we ran out of chicken.
所以不幸的是，我们的鸡肉卖完了。
This means that we no longer have chicken.
这意味着我们不再有鸡肉了。
We sold all of the chicken.
我们把所有的鸡肉都卖光了。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, if you're in your car and all of a sudden you run out of gasoline, it
比如，如果你在车里，突然汽油用完了，那
means your car will stop running.
就意味着你的车会熄火。
That's very bad situation.
那是个很糟糕的情况。
So to run out of means to not have any more.
所以“用完了”意味着不再有了。
That's right.
没错。
So you ran out of money.
所以你的钱用完了。
Maybe you have no more money.
也许你没有钱了。
That's another bad situation.
那是另一个糟糕的情况。
So instead he ordered a burrito that included a side of guacamole and jalapenos.
所以他改点了一份卷饼，配有一份鳄梨酱和墨西哥辣椒。
Okay, so the reason we included this is because it's important to remember this as a phrase,
好的，我们提到这个是因为记住这个短语很重要，
a side of.
“一份”。
That's right.
没错。
So this burrito comes with a side of guacamole or this burrito has a side of beans.
所以这个卷饼配有一份鳄梨酱，或者这个卷饼配有一份豆子。
So a side of means a small portion, a little bit.
所以“一份”意味着小份，一点点。
That's right.
没错。
So the important part of a side of is that it doesn't come in the dish or inside the
所以“一份”的关键在于它不包含在主菜里，或者说不在卷饼里面。
burrito let's say.
比如说。
It just comes separately on a separate little plate.
它是单独放在一个小盘子里的。
Or it can come next to the main dish.
或者它可以放在主菜旁边。
So if the main dish is tacos, you can say I want tacos with a side of black beans.
所以如果主菜是塔可，你可以说我要塔可配一份黑豆。
You would get the black beans in a little bowl next to you.
你会得到一小碗黑豆放在你旁边。
But that's not the main thing.
但那不是主菜。
Exactly, exactly.
没错，没错。
So a side of.
所以是“配一份”。
Now for our last phrase, when we talked about the nachos, they came with melted cheese and
现在来看最后一个短语，当我们谈到玉米片时，它们配有融化的奶酪和
chili.
辣椒。
So what do we mean by they come with melted cheese and chili?
那么“它们配有融化的奶酪和辣椒”是什么意思呢？
Okay, so this verb to come with means that they have as a part of the dish.
好的，这个动词“配有”意思是它们作为菜肴的一部分。
So this is not a side.
所以这不是配菜。
Not like before when we were talking about a side of.
不像之前我们说的“配一份”。
This means that in the case of nachos, the nachos have on them, on top, cheese and chili.
这意味着在玉米片的情况下，玉米片上面有奶酪和辣椒。
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes if you go to McDonald's and you buy a meal, you get a burger and the burger
所以有时候你去麦当劳买套餐，你会得到一个汉堡，而汉堡
comes with French fries and a Coke included in the meal.
套餐里配有薯条和可乐。
Or you can say, unfortunately, this meal does not come with a drink.
或者你可以说，不幸的是，这个套餐不包含饮料。
So you have to order the drink extra.
所以你得额外点饮料。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a lot of great stuff.
好的，内容很丰富。
Let's take another look and we'll be right back.
我们再回顾一下，马上回来。
Hello, sir, welcome to Pistolero restaurant, may I take your order?
你好，先生，欢迎来到Pistolero餐厅，请问可以点餐吗？
Yes, I would like the chicken cheese enchiladas with a side of guacamole.
好的，我想要鸡肉奶酪恩奇拉达配一份鳄梨酱。
Sorry, sir, but we ran out of chicken.
抱歉，先生，我们的鸡肉卖完了。
May I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese quesadillas?
我可以推荐我们的美味牛肉卷饼或奶酪玉米饼吗？
Both include a side of guacamole and jalapenos.
两者都配有一份鳄梨酱和墨西哥辣椒。
Sure, I'll have the burrito.
好的，我要卷饼。
Do you have nachos?
你们有玉米片吗？
Of course, sir.
当然有，先生。
Our nachos come with melted cheese and chili.
我们的玉米片配有融化的奶酪和辣椒。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Would you like anything to drink?
您想喝点什么吗？
Sure, I'll have a Corona.
好的，我要一杯科罗娜啤酒。
All right, so Mexican food, very, very delicious.
好了，墨西哥菜非常非常美味。
And as we see, it has a lot of cheese in most dishes.
而且我们看到，大多数菜肴里都有很多奶酪。
It does, a lot of cheese and also a lot of tortillas.
确实，很多奶酪，还有很多玉米饼。
So tortillas are these usually round, flat, pancake like things.
所以玉米饼通常是圆形、扁平、像煎饼一样的东西。
They're not sweet, they're savory.
它们不甜，是咸味的。
And you usually put things in them like tacos or fajitas or burritos.
你通常会把东西放进去，比如塔可、法吉塔或卷饼。
That's right.
没错。
And there's two kinds, right?
有两种，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So you have tortillas that are made from flour that are usually white.
所以有用面粉做的玉米饼，通常是白色的。
And then you have corn tortillas that are made from corn and they're usually a little
还有用玉米做的玉米饼，它们通常有点
bit more yellow.
更黄一些。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually, Mexican food is very, very good, but usually it's a little bit spicy.
所以实际上，墨西哥菜非常非常好吃，但通常有点辣。
So if you don't really like a spicy food, you should tell the waiter or waitress to
所以如果你不太喜欢辣的食物，你应该告诉服务员
not make it spicy.
不要做得太辣。
That's right.
没错。
If you don't eat spicy food, you certainly don't want to eat any jalapeno peppers.
如果你不吃辣的食物，你肯定不想吃任何墨西哥辣椒。
That's right.
没错。
I'm actually not really a fan of spicy food.
我其实不太喜欢辣的食物。
So for example, I really cannot eat jalapeno peppers.
所以比如，我真的吃不了墨西哥辣椒。
See, I'm the opposite.
看，我正好相反。
I love spicy food.
我喜欢辣的食物。
So I often order green enchiladas, which have a spicy jalapeno green sauce.
所以我经常点绿色恩奇拉达，它们有辣的墨西哥辣椒绿色酱汁。
Yeah, they're very, very spicy.
是的，它们非常非常辣。
So this is part of our mini series that we have all about world foods.
这是我们关于世界美食的迷你系列的一部分。
We've already taken a look at Italian food.
我们已经看过意大利菜了。
We have Mexican food.
我们有墨西哥菜。
Next we'll be looking at Indian food, Korean food, a lot of great international foods coming
接下来我们会看印度菜、韩国菜，还有很多很棒的国际美食即将
up.
推出。
Yummy.
好吃。
So let us know, do you like Mexican food?
所以告诉我们，你喜欢墨西哥菜吗？
Have you ever had Mexican food?
你吃过墨西哥菜吗？
And if we left off some kind of Mexican food like tacos, let us know.
如果我们漏掉了某种墨西哥菜，比如塔可，请告诉我们。
That's right.
没错。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
All right.
好的。
See you guys next week.
下周见。